Curriculum Vitae

SEKH ANWAR ALLI

Post Applied for Procurement Manager

Cell No. +91-9913285525 +91-8780467905

E-mail: shine.sekhanwaralli@gmail.com

Present Address: Sarkhei

Ahmedabad, Gujarat-382210

CAREER OBJECTIVE:

Strongly desire to pursue my career in a well-established industry. I have enclosed **14 Year's** experience of **Multi National Company & General Contracting comapany** in India & Saudi Arabia in the field of **Procurement (Civil).** Keeping the present scenario in mind, I look for an opportunity that would bring out the best of my potential.

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION:

- M.B.A (MARKETING & HR): From Sikkim Manipal University, Dehradun.
- **B Tech Engineering :** From B.P.U.T in 2006-2010.
- **B Sc (Physics-Hons):** From F M University-2001-2004.
- Intermediate (Science): From C.H.S.E BOARD, Odisha in 2000.
- Matriculation: From B.S.E. Board, Odisha in 1998.

TECHNICAL QUALIFICATION:

- Professionally Experts in SAP and ERP.
- Operating Systems exposure: Windows XP, Window 7
- MS Office 2000,2003,2007
- Excel, Power point, MS-word, MS-Access, MS-Outlook & Internet

ORGANIZATIONAL EXPERIENCE DETAILS:

Total 14 Years of Experience in the field Of Procurement

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY:

Duration : DECEMBER 2022 TO TILL DATE.

Designation : Dy Manager-Purchase (Civil)

Current Name of Company : DILIP BUILDCON LIMITED

Project Handling : SAHEBGANJ-MANIHARI PROJECT (GANGA BRIDGE PROJECT)

SAHEBGANJ NHAI BYPASS ROAD PROJECT

Duration : SEPTEMBER 2021 TO DECEMBER 2022.

Designation : Procurement Manager (Civil)

Name of Company : DIANKA INDUSTRIES (INDIA) PVT LTD (A SUBSIDIARY OF

ARCHON POWERINFRA (INDIA) PVT LTD)

Project Handling : NATIONAL HIGHWAY PROJECT (NHAI) HIMMAT NAGAR IN

GUJARAT, GMRC METRO PROJECT IN AHMEDABAD, ARVIND

FORRESTE IN GANDHI NAGAR, JNC UNIVERSITY BALLIA IN UP , MAHARAJA SUHEL DEV STATE UNIVERSITY AZAMGARH IN

UP, HPCL SITARGANJ IN UTTRAKHAND, NBCC AT J&K.

Duration : APRIL 2019 TO AUGUST 2021.

Designation : Procurement Manager (Civil)

Name of Company : ARCHON POWERINFRA (INDIA) PVT LTD

Project Handling : LPG BOTTLING PLANT IN IOCL MOTIHARI BIHAR, AHMEDABAD

GMRC METRO, JNC UNIVERSITY BALLIA IN UP, IOCL

REFINERY PARADEEP IN ODISHA & NBCC AT J&K

Duration : AUGUST 2016 to MARCH 2019

Designation : Procurement Manager(Civil)

Name of Company : HILAL AL ARABIA CONT. EST. (K.S.A)

Project Handling : SABIC-SBR (SAUDI KAYAN, SHARQ, SAFCO, UNITED, AL RAZI,

GAS, SAB TANK, SAUDI SPECIALITY, AL BAYRONI , IBN SINA) OTHERS PROJECTS (TAMIMI-C (CONSTRUCTION), TAMIMI-J

(JANITORIAL), AL MASHARIQ, REZAYAT, ASACCO)

Company Profile : GENERAL CONSTRUCTION WORK.

Duration : AUGUST 2015 TO JULY 2016
Designation : Procurement Executive

Name of Company : K. INDUSTRIES
Company Profile : MANUFACTURER

Duration : APRIL 2014 TO JULY 2015
Designation : Procurement Executive
Name of Company : EXL SERVICES PVT. LTD

Company Profile : MULTI NATIONAL COMPANY

Duration : JANUARY 2010 TO MARCH 2014

Designation : Procurement Executive

Name of Company : GEMINI COSMETICS PVT. LTD.

Company Profile : MANUFACTURER

JOB RESPONSIBILITIES:

Joined this current company in 2022 as **Dy. Manager-Purchase (Civil)** in Sahibganj (Jharkhad) and my job responsibilities cover the following points given below,

- Daily review Meeting with team regarding status and work allocation.
- Provide materials & services to project site as per urgent requirement by project site staff.
- Preparing RFQ's and forwarding it to relevant suppliers to obtain quotations.
- Contact with suppliers and follow up for timely receipt of materials & delivery of the materials.
- Maintaining records of various categories of approved suppliers.
- Proactive updates to Project Manager on delivery/ services to meet project deadlines.
- Excellence experience in power of negotiation with vendors with best quality of laboratory
- Obtaining payment details from Finance and reconciling with vendors.
- Retaining/ deleting of vendors based on vendor performance evaluation.
- Generating different purchase report as per requirement by management.
- Liaison with finance team and ensure timely release of payments.
- Verification of Payment claim form based on PO and Invoice.
- Introducing new vendors for healthy competition.
- Evaluating vendor performance based on PQD (Product/ Quality/ Delivery) for higher quality of services from vendor.
- A good knowledge of materials & supplier of Electrical, Mechanical, Tube Fitting, Piping, Safety & General Trading.
- Verify every replicated orders and the stock availability. Obtain the orders from end users & complete the task on given time and check the all inventory.

- Schedule meeting for the company needs with supplier/dealer/distributer/agent for negotiation.
- Aware & completed so many shutdowns job and completed the all task in critical situation.
- Answering and replying all phone calls and all mails (100+ mail receive & reply in a day).
- Preparing notes for quotation, MRF (Materials Request Form), P.O & D.O.
- Develop and maintain constructive and cooperative working relationships with colleagues and management.
- Experience in various facets of marketing & procuring materials.
- Consistent performer with a strong track record, positive attitude, with ability to handle assignments under high pressure.
- Material Procurement receipt, physical inspection, stacking, maintaining minimum & maximum level of critical & fast moving items.
- Experienced with implementing systems of inventory management avoiding over-stocking or wastage.
- Expertise in developing local vendors, reducing the cost of procurement of material
- Screening of requisitions prior to forwarding for procurement incharge .
- Reconciliation vendor statement with in house system statement.
- Experience in purchase activities (Forecasting, Planning & Execution)
- Keeping all procurement documents.
- Problem solving techniques using quality tools.

ADAPTABILITY & PERSONAL SKILLS:

Good communication, team work, organizing skills, call, time management, active listening & learning. Always willing to learn more for bright future career. Interpersonal skills very excellent.

PERSONAL DETAILS:

Father's Name : Sekh Mansur Alli Mother's Name : Sahenaj Begum Date of Birth : 24-04-1983

Nationality : Indian

Marital Status : Married

Gender : Male

Language Known : English, Hindi , Urdu ,Arabi & Odiya

DECLARATION:

In view of the above particulars if given a chance to serve under your kind guidance I can assure you Sir, I'll discharge my duties to your entire satisfaction and the order of all my superiors.

Date: Signature
Place: SEKH ANWAR ALLI